<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>File Storage on Layer5 Academy</title><link>https://cloud.layer5.io/academy/learning-paths/98e16360-a366-4b78-8e0a-031da07fdacb/intro-storage/file-storage/</link><description>Recent content in File Storage on Layer5 Academy</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://cloud.layer5.io/academy/learning-paths/98e16360-a366-4b78-8e0a-031da07fdacb/intro-storage/file-storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Benefits - File Storage</title><link>https://cloud.layer5.io/academy/learning-paths/98e16360-a366-4b78-8e0a-031da07fdacb/intro-storage/file-storage/content/benefits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloud.layer5.io/academy/learning-paths/98e16360-a366-4b78-8e0a-031da07fdacb/intro-storage/file-storage/content/benefits/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="overview">&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#overview" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Suppose your organization requires a centralized, easily accessible, affordable way to store files and folders. In that case, file-level storage is a good approach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The benefits of file storage include the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Simplicity: File storage is the simplest, most familiar, and most straightforward approach to organizing files and folders on a computer’s hard drive or NAS device. You name files, tag them with metadata, and store them in folders under a hierarchy of directories and subdirectories. It is not necessary to write applications or code to access your data.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>File Sharing: File storage is ideal for centralizing and sharing files on a Local Area Network (LAN). Files stored on a NAS device are easily accessible by any computer on the network that has the appropriate permission rights.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Common Protocols: File storage uses standard file-level protocols such as Server Message Block (SMB), Common Internet File System (CIFS), or Network File System (NFS). Utilize a Windows or Linux operating system (or both). Standard protocols like SMB/CIFS and NFS allow you to read and write files to a Windows-based or Linux-based server over your Local Area Network (LAN).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Protection: Storing files on a separate, LAN-connected storage device offers you a level of data protection should your network computer experience a failure. Cloud-based file storage services provide additional data protection and disaster recovery by replicating data files across multiple geographically dispersed data centers.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Affordability: File storage using a NAS device allows you to move files off of expensive computing hardware and onto a more affordable LAN-connected storage device. Moreover, suppose you choose to subscribe to a cloud file-storage service. In that case, you eliminate the expense of on-site hardware upgrades and the associated ongoing maintenance and operation costs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Accessibility: Files stored in the cloud can be accessed from anywhere with an internet connection, making it convenient for users to retrieve their files on different devices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Scalability: Cloud storage allows users to quickly scale up or down their storage capacity based on their needs. This eliminates the need to purchase additional hardware or upgrade local storage devices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Data Backup and Recovery: Cloud storage providers typically offer built-in data backup and recovery features, ensuring that files are protected from hardware failures, accidents, or other forms of data loss.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Collaboration: Cloud storage enables seamless collaboration among users by allowing them to share files and folders with others. Multiple users can work on the same file simultaneously, making it easier to collaborate on projects.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Syncing: Cloud storage often includes file synchronization features, automatically updating files across multiple devices. This ensures that users always have the latest version of their files, regardless of the device they are using.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Details - File Storage</title><link>https://cloud.layer5.io/academy/learning-paths/98e16360-a366-4b78-8e0a-031da07fdacb/intro-storage/file-storage/content/details/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloud.layer5.io/academy/learning-paths/98e16360-a366-4b78-8e0a-031da07fdacb/intro-storage/file-storage/content/details/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="explained">&lt;strong>Explained&lt;/strong>&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#explained" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>File storage has been around for considerably longer than object or block storage. It is something most people are familiar with. You name your files, place them in folders, and nest them under more folders to form a set path. This way, files are organized into a hierarchy, with directories and sub-directories. Each file also has a limited set of metadata associated with it, such as the file name, the date it was created, and the date it was last modified.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Use Cases - File Storage</title><link>https://cloud.layer5.io/academy/learning-paths/98e16360-a366-4b78-8e0a-031da07fdacb/intro-storage/file-storage/content/use-cases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloud.layer5.io/academy/learning-paths/98e16360-a366-4b78-8e0a-031da07fdacb/intro-storage/file-storage/content/use-cases/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="overview">&lt;strong>Overview&lt;/strong>&lt;a class="td-heading-self-link" href="#overview" aria-label="Heading self-link">&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Cloud file storage provides the flexibility to support and integrate with existing applications, plus the ease of deploying, managing, and maintaining all your files in the cloud. These two key advantages allow organizations to support various applications and verticals. Use cases such as large content repositories, development environments, media stores, and user home directories are ideal workloads for cloud-based file storage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here are some example use cases for file storage:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>